Guide to the Morris Raphael Cohen Papers 1898-1981
University of Chicago Library
- Series I: Personal and Professional Correspondence, 1899-1946
  - Correspondence, Van Beuren, Frederick T. Van Doren, Carl Van Doren, Mark Van Meter, I. Van Norden, Langdon Varady, Samuel Vaudrin, Philip Velikovsky, Immanuel Verne, Samuel Veron, N. Edward Viets, Henry R. Villard, Oswald Garrison Vineburg, Alexander Vivas, Eliseo Vladeck, B. Charney (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Wagner, Augustus H. Wagner, Robert Wahl, Dr. G. Walcott, Gregory D. (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, Wald, Lillian Walden, William Waldheim, Franklin Waldman, Morris Waldo, S. E. Wallace, Joseph Wallace, Schuyler Wallach, Sidney Watt, James Watton, S. B. Warburg, Edward Warburg, Felix (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, Ward, Henshaw Wardlaw, Donald Warren, Preston Warsoff, Louis A. Waterman, L. J. Weber, Dr. J. A. Wechsler, I. S. Weschler, Nancy Weill, Elsa Wein, Harold Weiner, R. William Weisfeld, Israel H. Weisman, Janet Weiss, Albert Weiss, Charles Weiss, Israel Weiss, Franz Joseph (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, Weiss, Paul (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, Weiss, Samuel Weissenberg, Alexander Wendel, T. V. Werner, Walter Wessel, Harvey E. Westgate, Lewis G. Weston, S. Burns Weyl, Herman Weyl, Walter Wheeler, Everett P. Wheeler, [Percy I.] Wheelwright, Phillip E. White, Morton Whitehead, Alfred North Whiteson, Rita Whitman, Hazel Whitney, Florence Whitney, William D. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Weiner, Phillip Wiggins, Lee Wigmore, John (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Wilcox, Elmer A. Wilder, Iris W. Wilkins, Ernest H. Willcox, W. F. Willen, Joseph Willert, Paul Willits, Joseph H. Wilson, Charles H. Wilson, John Wilson, M. L. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Wilson, Robert Wind, Edgar Winestine, Norman Winkler, Harold Winks, Gordon Winston, G. E. A. Winter, Benjamin Wirth, Louis Wise, Hazel Wise, Jonah Wise, Stephen (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Wissler, Clark Witmer, S. W. Woehlke, Walter V. Wolcott, Samuel H. Wolf, Heinrich F. Wolfe, Bertram D. Wolff, Rose Wolfson, H. N. Wolfson, Theresa Wohn, Sheldon (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Wolsey, Louis Wood, Austin B. Woodbridge, Frederick Woodruff, Lorande Lass Woods, Elizabeth R. Woods, James (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Woods, Herbert Woolcott, A. Word, Emily Wormser, I. Maurice Wriggram, A.E. Wright, H. N. Wright, Warren Wuorinen, John H. Wynne, Arthur V. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Yale University Yard, James M. Yarmolinsky, A. Yiddish Scientific Institute Young, Donald Yntema, Hessel E. Younker, Ira M. Zelenko, Lizzie Zilsel, Edgar Zinman, M. E. Zorn, Lewis E. Zuckerman, A. Die Zukunft Zunser, Ch. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Family Correspondence (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence in Hungarian and Hebrew (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Testimonial dinner in honor of Morris Cohen, 1927, confirmations and replies (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Unidentified correspondence (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Unidentified correspondence (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Unidentified correspondence (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Unidentified correspondence (Box 13, Folder 15)
- Series II: Writings by Cohen and Students' Papers, 1898-1938
  - Art, notes (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - "Subjectivism in Aesthetics," notes (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - "Dante," draft (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Greek Literature, notes (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - "Literature and Life, by Christian Collen," notes (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - "Romanticism," notes (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - History and Philosophy of Art, notes (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - History and Philosophy of Art, notes (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - "Economic and Social Planning," carbon typescript, March 1932 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - "A Critique of Marx's Theory of Value," carbon typescript (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Value Theory, notes (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - "Towards the Understanding of Karl Marx, 1933, by Sidney Hook," (book review), annotated typescript (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - "The Social Basis of Individualism," annotated carbon typescript; "The Cult of Illegality," annotated typescript, and untitled (on revolution and reform), annotated typescript (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - "The Mental and Material Basis of Socialism," Lecture, April 1899 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Notes on labor contracts, accident and workmen's insurance, etc. (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - "The Aporias of the Ethical Ideal," draft (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - "Morality," draft (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - "The Illusion of Professional Moralists," draft (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - "The Illusion of Morality," notes (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Morality, miscellaneous notes (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - "The Illusion of Freedom," notes (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - "Practical Ethical Problems," notes (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - "The Fifth Book of Aristotle's Ethics," notes (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - "The Problem of Evil," draft; and "The Basis of Ethics," notes (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - "Ethical Questions- the Is and the Ought," draft (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - "Ethical Relativism," annotated typescript (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous notes on "reason" and "certainty" (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous notes on the idea of "good" (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - "The Metaphysics of Free Will," notes (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - "Axiology," annotated typescript (holograph notation, upper recto- "incomplete but important, M.R.C. 2/4/46"); The Carus Lectures; The Meaning of Human History (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - "Foreword to Carus Lectures," draft, annotated typescript (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - History and Philosophy of Art, notes annotated tyepscript (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - History and Philosophy of Art, notes, annotated typescript/holograph draft (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - History and Philosophy of Art, notes, annotated typescript/holograph draft (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - History and Philosophy of Art, notes, annotated typescript/holograph draft, typed inserts (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - History and Philosophy of Art, notes, annotated typescript/holograph draft, typed inserts (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Chapter Two; "The Metaphysics of History," holograph and annotated typescript draft (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - History and Philosophy of Art, Section 2; "Ideas and Materials," holograph and annotated typescript draft (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - History and Philosophy of Art, Section 3; "Change and Persistence," holograph and annotated typescript draft (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - History and Philosophy of Art, Section 4; "Unity and Diversity," holograph and annotated typescript draft (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - "The Idea of Possibility in Human History" (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Carus lecture, notes (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - "Causality in History," annotated typescript and holograph notes (Box 16, Folder 2-3)
  - "Causation," holograph outline; Chapter II; "The Logic of History," section 8; "Purpose in History," annotated typescript; Chapter II; "The Logic of History," section 9; "The Extent of Human Volition," annotated typescript; and Chapter II; "The Logic of History," section 10; "Obstacles to the Achievement of Human Purpose." (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - "The Geographic Factor in History," annotated typescript with bibliography (Box 16, Folder 5-7)
  - "The Geographic Factor in History," notes (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - "The Influence of Great Men," notes (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Chapter 6, "The Biological Elements," notes (Box 16, Folder 10-11)
  - "The Biological Elements," draft (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Chapter 8, "The Institutional Approach to History," draft (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Chapter 8, "Notes on Economics..." (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Chapter 8, "Nature of Civilization and Culture" (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Chapter 8, "The Liberal Interpretation of History" (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Chapter 9, "Historical Development," section, "Critique of Traditional Liberalism" (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Chapter 10, "Value of the Tragic View of History" (Box 16, Folder 18-9)
  - Chapter 10, "On the Ethical Interpretation of History" (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - "The Tragic View of History," typescript draft (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Carus lecture, notes (Box 17, Folder 2-7)
  - Chapter One, "The Task of the Historian," tyepscript draft (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Section on Chapter 2; and Chapter Three, "Importance and Possibility in History," annotated typescript draft (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Chapter 4, "Linkage of Human Events," typescript draft (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Section of Chapter 5 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Chapter 7, "Great Men in History," typescript draft (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Chapter 8, "The Institutional Approach to History," typescript draft (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Chapter 9, "On the Ethical Interpretation of History," typescript draft (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Chapter 1, "The Task of the Historian," typescript draft (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - "The Categories of History; Change and Persistence," typescript draft (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - "The Transition from Agricultural to Industrial Society," typescript draft (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous typescript drafts (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - "Purpose in History," typescript draft (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - "The Absolute Rights of the Individual," typescript draft (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Table of Contents and Chapter 1, "The Task of the Historian," typescript draft, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Chapter 2, "Metaphysics and History," typescript draft (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Chapter 3, "Importance and Possibility in History," typescript draft (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Chapter 4, "The Linkage of Human Events," typescript draft (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Chapter 5, "The Geographic Factor in History," typescript draft (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Chapter 6, "The Biologic Element in History," typescript draft (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Chapter 7, "Great Men in History," typescript draft (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Chapter 8, "The Institutional Approach to History," typescript draft (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Chapter 9, "Patterns of Historic Development," typescript draft (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Chapter 10, "The Tragic View of History," typescript draft (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Chapter 1, "The Background of the American Tradition," annotated typescript draft (Box 18, Folder 4-6)
  - Chapter 1, notes (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Chapter 1, annotated typescript draft (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Chapter 1, preface and typescript draft (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Chapter 2, "Religious Thought," notes and annotated typescript draft (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Chapter 2, notes (Box 18, Folder 11-2)
  - Chapter 2, annotated typescript draft, notes, and Morris Cohen, "Contemporary Religious Thought in America," October 5, 1931, annotated typescript (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Chapters 1 and 2, annotated typescript and holograph drafts (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Foreword, annotated typescript draft (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Chapter 1, "The Background of the American Tradition," annotated typescript draft (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Chapter 2, "American Ideas on History," annotated typescript draft (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Chapter 3, "Scientific Thought," annotated typescript draft (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Chapter 4, "Economic Thought," annotated typescript draft (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Chapter 5, "Political Thought," annotated typescript draft (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Chapter 6, "Legal Thought," edited version of earlier paper published as "A Critical Sketch of Legal Philosophy in America," and annotated typescript draft (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Chapter 6, "Legal Thought," edited version of earlier paper published as "A Critical Sketch of Legal Philosophy in America," and annotated typescript draft and Chapter 7, "Religious Thought," annotated typescript draft (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Chapter 7, "Religious Thought," annotated typescript draft (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Draft #4 (incomplete copy) annotated typescript (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Draft, annotated typescript (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Chapter 1, annotated typescript draft (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Chapters 1-5, annotated typescript draft (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Chapter 6, annotated typescript draft, and notes (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Chapters 7-9, annotated typescript draft (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - "American Musical Thought," annotated typescript draft (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - "Scientific Thought in America," annotated typescript draft (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - "Political Thought in America," annotated typescript draft (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - "Contemporary American Thought," Chapters 8-9, annotated typescript draft (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - "Contemporary American Thought in Sociology," lecture, annotated typescript draft (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - "Contemporary American Thought in Science," lecture, annotated typescript draft (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - "Contemporary American Thought in Psychology," lecture, annotated typescript draft (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Chapter 8, "Aesthetics," annotated typescript draft (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Chapter 8, notes and annotated typescript draft (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Chapter 9, "General Philosophy," annotated typescript draft (Box 21, Folder 3-4)
  - "American Literature and Literary Criticism," typescript draft (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - "Reflections on Literature," holograph draft (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Reflections on Literature," holograph draft, notes (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - "Contemporary American Thought in Literature," annotated typescript draft, and holograph notes (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - "Contemporary American Thought in Literature," notes (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - "Contemporary American Thought in Music," holograph notes (Box 21, Folder 10-16)
  - "Contemporary American Philosophy," annotated typescript draft (Box 21, Folder 17-8)
  - "Political Thought in America," annotated typescript draft (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - "American Political Thought," annotated typescript draft (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - "Liberalism in American Foreign Relations," annotated typescript draft (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Political theory, notes (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - American Psychology, notes (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - "Scientific Thought in America," annotated typescript draft (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - "Scientific Thought in America,", notes (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - "Sociology," annotated typescript draft (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - "Sociology," annotated typescript draft (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - "Sociology," notes (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - "Literary Criticism," annotated typescript draft (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - "Contemporary American Thought," lecture 1, typescript lecture notes, September 28, [1931] (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - "Political Thought," lecture 3, typescript lecture notes, October 12, 1931 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - "Contemporary American Thought in Economics," lecture 4, typescript lecture notes (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - "Contemporary American Thought in Science," lecture 5, typescript lecture notes, Oct. 26, 1931 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - "Contemporary American Thought in Psychology," lecture 7, typescript lecture notes (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - "Contemporary American Thought in Art," lecture 10, typescript lecture notes, November 3, 1931 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous typescript notes on sociology (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - "American Thought; A Critical Sketch," outline and typescript draft (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - "The Construction of Intellectual Life in America," holograph notes (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Notes on American Thought (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Notes on Boas, Dewey, Veblen, etc. (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - "Thought of the XIXth Century," typescript draft (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - "The General Background of the Thought of the Nineteenth century," lecture 1, draft (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - "The Widening of the Human Horizon," lecture 2, draft (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - "The Liberalism of the Eighteenth century," lecture 3, draft (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - "Reaction Against the Rationalism of the Enlightenment," lecture 4, draft (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - "Reaction Against the Rationalism of the Enlightenment," continued, lecture 5, draft (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - "The General Background of the Thought of the Nineteenth century," and "Thought of the Nineteenth century," annotated typescript drafts (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - "Thought of the Nineteenth century - the Cult of History," typescript lecture, February 5, 1924 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - "Thought of the Nineteenth century - Psychology," typescript lecture, February 12, 1924 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Class attendance records for Cohen's class in Philosophy, 1929-1932 (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - "Thought of the Nineteenth century - Irrationalism," typescript lecture, February 26, 1924 (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - "Thought of the Nineteenth century - Individualism," typescript lecture, March 4, 1924 (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - "Thought of the Nineteenth century - Nationalism," typescript lecture, March 11, 1924 (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - "Thought of the Nineteenth century - Socialism," typescript lecture, March 18. 1924 (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - "Thought of the Nineteenth century," typescript outline (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - "Thought of the Nineteenth century," holograph notes (Box 22, Folder 34-35)
  - "Philosophy of History," typescript draft (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - "Philosophy of Civilization," holograph notes (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - "The Significance of the Roman Contribution to Civilization," holograph draft and notes (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - "Greek Philosophy" and the "Roman Empire," notes (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - "Roman Empire," notes (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Notes on history (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - "Purpose in History," rough draft (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - "Possibility in History," rough draft (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - "Miscellaneous Notes on Philosophy of History," notes (Box 23, Folder 9-10)
  - "Art," miscellaneous notes (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - "American Legal Thought," annotated typescript draft (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - "American Legal Thought," miscellaneous notes (Box 23, Folder 13-4)
  - "Justice Holmes," typescript draft (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - "The Background and Development of Legal Philosophy in the Americas," typescript lecture read to the Pan-American Scientific Congress, 1940, with letter from Cohen to his son Felix, May 4, 1940, T.L.S., 1 p.; and undated, A.L.S., 1 p. (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Notes on the Supreme Court (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Supreme Court, annotated typescript draft (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Philosophy of Law (Hebraic), annotated typescript draft (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - "The Values in Legal Theory," annotated typescript draft and other notes (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - "The Supreme Court. Is the Judicial Review Necessary?" typescript address to the New School Forum, April 24 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - "Fallacies and the Court," annotated typescript draft (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - "Constitutional and Natural Rights in 1789 and Since," carbon typescript draft; "What is Justice?" and other drafts concerning philosophy of law (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - "The Law of Contracts," typescript (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - "The Law of Contracts," annotated typescript draft (Box 23, Folder 25-6)
  - Criminality, holograph notes (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - "Cause of Crime," notes (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - "Difference of Degree of Criminality," notes (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - "Criminal Statistics," notes (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - "Criminal Law," tyepscript draft (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - "Justice in Punishment," typescript draft and notes (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - "Law and Ethics," annotated typescript draft (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - "Morality and Social Ethics," draft (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - "Law and Ethics," draft (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - "Law and Ethics," notes (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - "Criminal Law," typescript lecture (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - "Moral as Utilitarian or Engineering View of Criminal Law," notes (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - "Theories of Justice," notes (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - "Justice," typescript drafts (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - 18th century thought, typescript draft (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - "Italian contributions to the Philosophy of Law," holograph draft (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Legal system, notes (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - "Legalism and Clericalism," partial typescript draft and holograph outline and notes (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - "An Outline of Lecture 1," typescript draft (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Philosophy of law, miscellaneous notes (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - "Problems of Legal Method," holograph draft (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - "Law and Psychology," typescript draft (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - "Law and Sociology," holograph notes (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - "Law and Custom," miscellaneous notes (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - "Evidence and Proof," notes (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - "Law and Politics," typescript draft (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - "The Retributive, Expiatory or Retaliatory Theory," typescript draft (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - "Imprisonment," typescript draft (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - "The Causes of Crime," typescript draft (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - "The Sanctity of Law; A Critique," typescript draft (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - "Social Contract Theory and State of Nature," notes (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Philosophy of Law, notes (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - "American Political Theory," notes (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - "Law, Religion and Ethics," draft (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - Law and Political Science, notes (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - "The Bill of Rights Theory, " draft (Box 24, Folder 30)
  - "Gray," draft (Box 24, Folder 31)
  - "The Chief Justice of Maine," draft (Box 24, Folder 32)
  - "Law and Logical System," draft (Box 24, Folder 33)
  - "The Legend of Magna Charta," typescript (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - "Introduction to the Philosophy of Law, by Dean Pound," (book review for The New Republic,) typescript carbon draft, November 29, 1922; "The Bill of Rights Again," typescript draft; "Law and Morals," (The McNair Lectures, 1923, University of North Carolina), typescript draft; "History in Slang," typescript page (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - "Philosophy and Legal Science," typescript draft (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Contract, Law, Democracy and Collectivism, notes (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - "Law," (course outline), notes, and "Property," typescript lecture (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - "Topics in Legal Philosophy," bibliography, outline and syllabus for course at Columbia University (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Property, personal freedom, notes (Box 25, Folder 7-8)
  - "Equality Before the Law," notes; "The Law of Persons," notes; "Essays in Legal Philosophy," notes (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - "Power of Corporations," notes (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - "Declaration of Will," notes (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - History of philosophy, notes (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - "Justice and the Legal Order," notes (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - "Theory of Justice," notes (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - "General Legal Philosophy," notes (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - "Legal Idealism," notes (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - "Limits of Legal Reform," notes (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Legislation, notes (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - "The Logic of Imperatives," notes (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Interpretation, notes (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Jurisprudence, notes (Box 26, Folder 1-2)
  - Justice and Liberty, notes (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - "Philosophy of Law," notes (Box 26, Folder 4-5)
  - Precedent, notes (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - "Property and Power in Civic Law," notes (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - "Rational Distribution of Property," notes (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - "Property," typescript draft (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - "Justification of Private Property," notes (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Ethics and Criminal Law, notes (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - "Law and Logic," notes (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - "Oliphant," notes (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Universalism, notes (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - "Free Law," notes (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - "Philosophy of Law," course syllabus (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Willoughby, Holmes, etc., notes (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - "Constitutional and Natural Rights in 1789 and Since," typescript draft (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 27, Folder 2)